#!/usr/bin/env python3

quiz_questions = [
    {
        "question": "Which of these websites are safer to access?",
        "options": [
            "http://www.mystore.com/shop/shoes",
            "https://www.paypa1-secure.com/login?sessionid=1234567890",
            "https://www.example.com/shop/clothes/women?category=dresses&sort=price-asc#summer-collection",
            "http://www.freeiphonedeals.com/win?prize=iphone&entry=1234"
        ],
        "answer":  "https://www.example.com/shop/clothes/women?category=dresses&sort=price-asc#summer-collection"
    },
    {
        "question": "Look at this URL and label the different sections: https://www.example.com/shop/clothes/women?category=dresses&sort=price-asc#summer-collection",
        "options": ["Domain Name, Top-level Domain, Subdomain, File Path, Anchor, Parameter String, Scheme","Parameter String, Anchor, Scheme, Domain Name, File Path, Top-level Domain Subdomain", "Scheme, Domain Name, Top-level Domain, File Path, Parameter String, Anchor", "Anchor, Subdomain, Domain Name, Top-level Domain, Parameter String, Achor File Path"],
        "answer": "Scheme, Domain Name, Top-level Domain, File Path, Parameter String, Anchor"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the different types of phishing?",
        "options": [
            "Vising, Wheeling, Smoothing and Spill Phishing",
            "Spar Phising, Shearing Phishing, Vishingtin and Splashing",
            "Whaling, Spear Phishing, Vishing, and Smishing",
            "Whisper Phishing, Splicing, Spcing and Squishing"
        ],
        "answer": "Whaling, Spear Phishing, Vishing, and Smishing"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following characteristics suggest that a website may be harmful or fake?",
        "options": [
            "Uses HTTPS with a padlock",
            "Has misspelled URLs or domain names",
            "Provides clear contact information and an About Us page",
            "Is professional with no grammar errors"
        ],
        "answer": "Has misspelled URLs or domain names"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of HTTPS in a website URL?",
        "options": [
            "It indicates the website is unsecure",
            "It allows you to access the internet without a browser",
            "It ensures that the data sent between your browser and the website is encrypted"
        ],
        "answer": "It ensures that the data sent between your browser and the website is encrypted"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the 'File path' in a URL do?",
        "options": [
            "Identifies the server the website is hosted on",
            "Takes you to a specific section of a website",
            "Specifies the secure connection to the website",
            "Tells the browser what page or resource to load within the website"
        ],
        "answer": "Tells the browser what page or resource to load within the website"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these domain extensions is most likely for a non-profit organization?",
        "options": [".com", ".org", ".edu", ".co.za"],
        "answer": ".org"
    },
    {
        "question": 'What should you do if you encounter a website with a lot of pop-ups, broken links, and "too good to be true" offers?',
        "options": [
            "Enter your information for the free offer",
            "Close the website immediately",
            "Share the link with friends",
            "Bookmark the site for future visits"
        ],
        "answer": "Close the website immediately"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which part of the URL tells you which organization owns the website?",
        "options": ["Scheme", "Domain name", "Subdomain", "Anchor"],
        "answer": "Domain name"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of a URL?",
        "options": [
            "To identify the location of a webpage on the internet",
            "To encrypt data sent between your browser and the website",
            "To serve as the homepage for a website",
            "To provide a secure login for users"
        ],
        "answer": "To identify the location of a webpage on the internet"
    },
]
